NARASIMHAN N. KANNAN

ENSCHEDE, NETHERLANDS

(+31) 645123419 \diamond narsim.kannan@gmail.com \diamond in

INTERESTS

I am interested broadly in the field of quantum theory. Coming from a mathematical background my experience and career focuses on information and operational aspects with applications in engineering and simulations. Apart from quantum things I am interested in philosophy of science, future of technology, and economics.

EMPLOYMENT

Quix Quantum BV

Feb. 2023 - present

Quantum Computing Architect

Enschede, Netherlands

- R&D work on near term device for quantum computing and applications.
- Writing simulation software for quantum optical computing.

Quix Quantum BV

Feb. 2022 - Feb. 2023

Quantum Software Engineer

Enschede, Netherlands

- R&D work on linear optical meshes, boson sampling.
- Writing and maintaining scientific software.
- Research in Quantum computing based on photonics.
- Supervision of master students.

CAPE GROEP

Data Scientist

Jan. 2020 - Jan. 2022

Enschede. Netherlands

- Building machine learning algorithms for product improvement.
- Time series forecasting for anomaly detection.
- Prediction models for logistic problems.

University of Twente

Feb. 2019 - July. 2019

Teaching Assistant for Complex Analysis

Enschede, Netherlands

- Supervised bachelor level students in tutorials.
- Evaluated and graded weekly homework.

Centrum Wiskunde & Informatica, QuSoft

Trainee

Sept. 2018 - Dec. 2018 Amsterdam, Netherlands

- I studied Quantum information theory focusing on entropy. : "Quantum Information and Entropy".
- Gained experience in working in a research environment and in producing scientific documents.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF TWENTE

Sept. 2017 - Oct. 2019

Master of Science, Applied Mathematics

Enschede, Netherlands

Focus: I followed the applied analysis track, taking courses in pure and applied topics.

Master Thesis: "An inverse scattering problem to reconstruct 3D refractive index distibutions"

Ramanujan School of Mathematical Sciences, Pondicherry University

July 2013 - July 2017

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science (on scholarship)

Pondicherry, India

Focus: This study was complemented with courses in mathematics and statistics, with an aim to continue research in mathematical sciences.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages Python, C, C++, MATLAB, Java

Programming Libraries PyTorch, numpy
Oral & Written Languages Tamil, English, Hindi

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

• Indoor bouldering and climbing.

- I play the guitar. Broad musical interest in blues-rock, progressive music.
- Digital and media art.
- Running, hiking and any kind of outdoor activity.